# **KARAN JAIN**

### FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

karanjain2212@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | +917987853691 | India |

#### **SUMMARY**

I'm a Full-Stack Web Developer who specializes in JavaScript, React, Redux, Node Js, and Ruby on Rails to build highly scalable software for tech companies. I have more than 3 Years of experience in the IT industry with analyzing Business Requirements, Software Development, Implementation and User support.

#### **SKILLS**

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, C#, HTML, CSS, ASP.NET (Web Forms and MVC),ADO.NET Back-End: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL

**Tools & Methods**: Git, GitHub, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools, ServiceNow **Professional**: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

#### **EXPERIENCE**

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

Aug, 2022 - June, 2023

- Mentorship of Junior Web Developers: Offering technical support and guidance through comprehensive code reviews.
- Improving Code Quality: Proposing suggestions for enhanced code organization, aiming to improve overall performance. Additionally, providing advice and tips to maintain motivation and longevity in the program.

Infosys Itd, Banglore, India

Banglore, India

Sr Systems Engineer

June, 2014 - July, 2017

- Handled entire support of Air Miles Middle East and Nectar ITALY, which involved setting up customized loyalty programs and managing the points flow.
- Designed UI using asp.net 4.0, C# to call the jobs and SSIS packages for creation of files and other data warehousing processes.
- Resolved daily service and technical issues raised by clients on ticketing System-Service Now
- Interaction with Product Owner and BA for understanding requirements for the Change requests.

Aryan Textiles, Jabalpur, India

Jabalpur, India

Founder, Proprietor

Jan, 2018 - Dec, 2022

- Managed the entire production process, ensuring high-quality standards, timely delivery, and optimization of operations.
- Demonstrated strong leadership by overseeing a 20-member team, driving smooth operations, and achieving production targets through effective guidance and coordination.
- With 4+ years of experience in sock manufacturing, I possess a versatile skill set in supply chain management, product development, team leadership, operations, growth driving, innovation, and process optimization. These skills are highly transferable and valuable in web development, enabling efficient delivery of complex, stakeholder-driven projects with data-driven decision making, high quality, and adherence to timelines and budgets.

## HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS Full Stack Web Developer

TheRecipieApp — A beautiful website showcasing a variety of food recipes of different categories. Users can also search according to specific ingredients.

- Built with: HTML,CSS,JAVASCRIPT,Web API's
- Github
- **Live Demo**

Shopping Spree - Innovative e-commerce website project utilizing React and Redux Toolkit. Features sleek, modern SAAS design, interactive elements (shopping cart, category page, detailed product descriptions), ensuring seamless user shopping experience.

- Built with: REACT ,REDUX ,REDUX toolkit, HTML,CSS,JAVASCRIPT, API
- Github
- Live Demo

Space Traveler's Hub - The Spacetravelers is a website for a company that provides commercial and scientific space travel services. It uses real live data from the SpaceX API. The website allows users to book rockets and join selected space missions.

- Built with: REACT ,REDUX ,REDUX toolkit, HTML,CSS,JAVASCRIPT, API
- Github
- Live Demo

MovieGeek - Website for shows and movies built with React and Redux toolkit. User-friendly interface for easy discovery and browsing of favorite content.

- Built with: REACT ,REDUX ,REDUX toolkit, HTML,CSS,JAVASCRIPT, API
- Github
- Live Demo

#### **EDUCATION**

**MICROVERSE** Aug, 2022 - June, 2023

- Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while
- simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

Infosys Global Education Center Mysore India

June, 2014 - December, 2014

### **Systems Engineer trainee**

- Trained in basic Computer technology in Infosys Leadership Institute at Mysore.
- Trained in OOPs Concepts, Oracle PL/SQL, C#, as major Programming languages. •
- Trained as well in Microsoft Dot-Net technologies like ASP.net, ADO.net, MVC and WCF.
- Completed the stream with CGPA score of 5.0/5.0.

Vellore Institute of technology, Vellore India

March, 2010 - April, 2014

## Btech, Biomedical Engineering

Completed with a CGPA score of 8/10.